Piyush Kakkar

Software Developer

A passionate and self-motivated software developer with high level of experience working on multiple projects. Versatile Full Stack Web Developer with more than 1+ year of professional experience developing consumer focused websites. Talented in project management, team leadership and independent problem-solving. Looking to join an organization where opportunity for growth and professional development is embraced.

EXPERIENCE

Smartprix Web Pvt. Ltd.

Noida IN

Software Developer

Jul. 2018 - Present

- Giveaway System: Developed and maintained a complete system to organize giveaways which includes task creation and verification, giveaway scheduling, winner declaration etc.
- Attendance Portal: Built a portal where employees can view their daily attendance and working hours based on punches from the biometric machine
- Browser Extension: Enhanced the working for Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox. Extended support for search and article pages. Also, designed and implemented various popups to be shown.
- Bots: Helped to create bots that replies on different social media platforms.
- Discussions: Redesigned discussions feature of the site.
- **Testing:** Prepared test plans and test cases for testing site frontend.
- Crawl Configs: Created configs to crawl data from several E commerce
- Bug Fixes: Engaged in development of code fixes and enhancements for continuous improvement.
- Open Source Contribution: Contributed to open source libraries of smartprix.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, JQuery, NodeJS, KoaJS, VueJs, MarkoJS, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, ObjectionJS and Python.

Cread Delhi, IN

Web Developer Intern

Mar. 2018 - May. 2018

- Created a web store for the company to sell products.
- Technologies: Angular 5, JavaScript and NodeJS.

Hindustan Petroleum Corp. Ltd.

Delhi, IN

Software Developer Intern

Jun. 2017 - Jul. 2017

- Created a Chat Application for employees that had features like One to One Chat, Broadcast Chat, Media Sharing, Smart Status etc.
- Technologies: AngularJS, NodeJS, JavaScript, Socket.IO and MySQL.

PROJECTS

Criminal Identification System

Jan. 2018 - Apr. 2018

The system provides a complete solution for a static image or video surveillance based face detection and recognition of criminals with higher accuracy and better response rate.

Technologies: Python, OpenCV, Haar Cascade, MySQL, Tkinter

Chat Application

Jun. 2017 - Jul. 2017

A web based Chat Application that provides features like One to One chat, Broadcast message to multiple people. Media sharing. Smart status etc. Technologies: AngularJS, NodeJS, MySQL, Socket.IO, JavaScript, JQuery

LetsSchedule Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2016

A task scheduling web application that can be used to schedule tasks with smart filters and reminders.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JQuery, NodeJS, and MySQL

PERSONAL DETAILS

kakkarpiyush96@gmail.com

(+91) 9873609932

1994 Outram Lines Kingsway Camp, G.T.B. Nagar, Delhi - 110009

in piyushk96

piyushk96

piyushk96

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

SCSS

JavaScript

 JQuery ExpressJS NodeJS Koa IS

VueJS

MarkoJS

C

C++

MySQL

PostgreSQL

GraphQL

TypeScript

Python

Java (Core)

ObjectionJS

KnexJS

Socket.IO

• Git

EDUCATION

Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology, **GGSIPU**

Bachelors of Technology (Information Technology) Aug. 2014 - Jun. 2018 82.1%

Coding Blocks

Delhi, IN

Web Development Training

Jun. 2016 - Aug. 2016

Delhi. IN

Secondary and Senior Secondary

Kulachi Hansraj Model School

Jul. 2013 - Jun. 2014 91.8% 12th Jul. 2011 - Jun. 2012 9 CGPA 10th

AWARDS

Feb. 2016

Robotics Competition by IIT Bombay 15th Position in Hotel Guest Service Theme.

Code Golf

May. 2015

Techsurge & Mridang '15

2nd Position